
<!DOCTYPE article
  PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD JATS (Z39.96) Journal Archiving and Interchange DTD with MathML3 v1.4 20241031//EN" "JATS-archivearticle1-4-mathml3.dtd">
<article xml:lang="en" article-type="research-article" dtd-version="1.4"><processing-meta base-tagset="archiving" mathml-version="3.0" table-model="xhtml" tagset-family="jats"><restricted-by>pmc</restricted-by></processing-meta><front><journal-meta><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-ta">J Med Internet Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="iso-abbrev">J Med Internet Res</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain-id">224</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="pmc-domain">jmir</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="nlm-id">100959882</journal-id><journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">jmir</journal-id><journal-title-group><journal-title>Journal of Medical Internet Research</journal-title></journal-title-group><issn pub-type="ppub">1439-4456</issn><issn pub-type="epub">1438-8871</issn><publisher><publisher-name>JMIR Publications Inc.</publisher-name></publisher></journal-meta><article-meta><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13372298</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcid-ver">PMC13372298.1</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaid">13372298</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmcaiid">13372298</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="pmid">42456184</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</article-id><article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">92863</article-id><article-version article-version-type="pmc-version">1</article-version><article-categories><subj-group subj-group-type="primary-section"><subject>Digital Health Reporting Standards, Quality and Transparency in e-Research</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Research Instruments, Questionnaires, and Tools</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Telehealth and Telemonitoring</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Design, Usability, and Evaluation of Research Instruments, Scales, and Measures</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Evaluation and Research Methodology for mHealth</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Development and Evaluation of Research Methods, Instruments and Tools</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="secondary-section"><subject>Tools and Software for Metascience and Research Integrity Research</subject></subj-group><subj-group subj-group-type="heading"><subject>Original Paper</subject></subj-group></article-categories><title-group><article-title>Developing a Core Outcome Set for the Evaluation of Remote Patient Monitoring Interventions Using the Sextuple Aim: Modified Delphi Study</article-title></title-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="author" corresp="yes"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0009-0007-5867-6547</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Heilig</surname><given-names initials="A">Anna</given-names></name><degrees>MSc</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref><xref rid="cor1" ref-type="corresp"/></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-7719-6182</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Bonten</surname><given-names initials="T">Tobias</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff2" ref-type="aff">2</xref><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0001-9282-9307</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>Recourt</surname><given-names initials="K">Kasper</given-names></name><degrees>MSc</degrees><xref rid="aff3" ref-type="aff">3</xref></contrib><contrib contrib-type="author"><contrib-id contrib-id-type="orcid" authenticated="false">https://orcid.org/0000-0002-5269-509X</contrib-id><name name-style="western"><surname>van den Akker-van Marle</surname><given-names initials="ME">M Elske</given-names></name><degrees>PhD</degrees><xref rid="aff1" ref-type="aff">1</xref></contrib><aff id="aff1"><label>1</label><institution content-type="department">Department of Medical Decision Making</institution>, <institution>Leiden University Medical Center</institution>, <addr-line>Albinusdreef 2</addr-line>, <addr-line content-type="city">Leiden</addr-line>, <addr-line content-type="state">South Holland</addr-line>, <addr-line>2333 ZA</addr-line>, <country>The Netherlands</country>, <phone>31 0630205719</phone></aff><aff id="aff2"><label>2</label><institution content-type="department">Department of Public Health and Primary Care</institution>, <institution>Leiden University Medical Center</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Leiden</addr-line>, <country>The Netherlands</country></aff><aff id="aff3"><label>3</label><institution content-type="department">National eHealth Living Lab (NeLL)</institution>, <institution>Leiden University Medical Center</institution>, <addr-line content-type="city">Leiden</addr-line>, <country>The Netherlands</country></aff></contrib-group><contrib-group><contrib contrib-type="editor"><name name-style="western"><surname>Law</surname><given-names initials="S">Stephanie</given-names></name></contrib></contrib-group><author-notes><corresp id="cor1">Anna Heilig, MSc, Department of Medical Decision Making, Leiden University Medical Center, Albinusdreef 2, Leiden, South Holland, 2333 ZA, The Netherlands, <phone>31 0630205719</phone>; <email xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="a.l.heilig@lumc.nl">a.l.heilig@lumc.nl</email></corresp></author-notes><pub-date pub-type="collection"><year>2026</year></pub-date><pub-date pub-type="epub"><day>15</day><month>7</month><year>2026</year></pub-date><volume>28</volume><issue-id pub-id-type="pmc-issue-id">504049</issue-id><elocation-id>e92863</elocation-id><history><date date-type="received"><day>04</day><month>2</month><year>2026</year></date><date date-type="rev-recd"><day>04</day><month>6</month><year>2026</year></date><date date-type="accepted"><day>04</day><month>6</month><year>2026</year></date></history><pub-history><event event-type="pmc-release"><date><day>15</day><month>07</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-live"><date><day>16</day><month>07</month><year>2026</year></date></event><event event-type="pmc-last-change"><date iso-8601-date="2026-07-16 00:25:18.737"><day>16</day><month>07</month><year>2026</year></date></event></pub-history><permissions><copyright-statement>Copyright © Anna Heilig, Tobias Bonten, Kasper Recourt, M Elske van den Akker-van Marle. Originally published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research (https://www.jmir.org)</copyright-statement><copyright-year>2026</copyright-year><license><ali:license_ref xmlns:ali="http://www.niso.org/schemas/ali/1.0/" specific-use="textmining" content-type="ccbylicense">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ali:license_ref><license-p>This is an open-access article distributed under the terms of the Creative Commons Attribution License (<ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/">https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/</ext-link>), which permits unrestricted use, distribution, and reproduction in any medium, provided the original work, first published in the Journal of Medical Internet Research (ISSN 1438-8871), is properly cited. The complete bibliographic information, a link to the original publication on <ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" ext-link-type="uri" xlink:href="https://www.jmir.org/">https://www.jmir.org/</ext-link>, as well as this copyright and license information must be included.</license-p></license></permissions><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" content-type="pmc-pdf" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863.pdf"/><self-uri xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:title="pdf" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863.pdf"/><abstract><title>Abstract</title><sec><title>Background</title><p>The rapid expansion of remote patient monitoring (RPM) interventions highlights the need for their comparison and evaluation. Current evaluation frameworks often fail to capture a multistakeholder perspective. Traditional health technology assessment approaches emphasize health and economic outcomes, providing an incomplete picture of RPM’s broader impact. The Sextuple Aim, encompassing health outcomes, costs, patient and provider experience, equity, and sustainability, offers a more comprehensive approach. Yet, the specific aspects that are important for capturing each domain for diverse stakeholders, and that could form a core outcome set (COS) for RPM evaluation, remain undefined.</p></sec><sec><title>Objective</title><p>This study aimed to identify the most important value aspects for evaluating RPM interventions from the Sextuple Aim domains.</p></sec><sec><title>Methods</title><p>Value aspects relevant to evaluating RPM interventions within the Sextuple Aim framework were identified in a review of the literature, and this initial set was refined through stakeholder meetings. Subsequently, 6 stakeholder groups completed 3 Delphi rounds. Patients and informal caregivers (25‐30 respondents per group) were recruited via a patient federation. Health care providers (20‐30 experts), managers, insurers, and researchers (10‐20 experts per group) were recruited. In each round, participants rated the importance of aspects on a 5-point Likert scale. In round 2, participants ranked aspects within each domain to determine their relative importance; in round 3, they ranked aspects across domains. A multicriteria consensus rule was used to select aspects for the preliminary COS. The COS was finalized during a multistakeholder expert meeting with 7 experts.</p></sec><sec><title>Results</title><p>Of the 171 respondents, 137 (80%) completed all Delphi rounds. The input set, formed through a literature search and meetings, contained 43 value aspects. The total set contained 47 aspects after the first round. After all 3 rating rounds, 33 of 47 (70%) value aspects met the predefined importance threshold. Ranking results from rounds 2 and 3 identified aspects prioritized within and across domains. In total, 26 (55%) aspects met the multicriteria consensus rule and formed the preliminary COS. During the final multistakeholder expert meeting involving subgroup exercises and moderated discussions, value aspects with conceptual overlap were merged, removed, or relocated. The final COS included 17 value aspects, with 1 additional emergent aspect identified during the expert meeting and included as a recommended item, which also resulted in full Sextuple Aim domain coverage.</p></sec><sec><title>Conclusions</title><p>An RPM Sextuple Aim COS comprising 17 value aspects and 1 recommended aspect was developed, providing a multidimensional and multistakeholder evaluation set. This COS provides a standardized, comprehensive basis for evaluating RPM interventions and can be used to support the validation and refinement of existing RPM evaluation tools. Future research may consider operationalizing the COS and its recommended aspect into measurable items and assessing its feasibility and uptake in practice.</p></sec></abstract><kwd-group kwd-group-type="author-keywords"><title>Keywords</title><kwd>digital health</kwd><kwd>remote patient monitoring</kwd><kwd>value assessment framework</kwd><kwd>Sextuple Aim</kwd><kwd>core outcome set</kwd><kwd>Delphi</kwd><kwd>telemonitoring</kwd><kwd>remote monitoring</kwd></kwd-group><custom-meta-group><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-qastatus</meta-name><meta-value>0</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-live</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-embargo</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-status-released</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-open-access</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-olf</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-manuscript</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-legally-suppressed</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-pdf</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-has-supplement</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-pdf-only</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-suppress-copyright</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-real-version</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-is-scanned-article</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-preprint</meta-name><meta-value>no</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-prop-in-epmc</meta-name><meta-value>yes</meta-value></custom-meta><custom-meta><meta-name>pmc-license-ref</meta-name><meta-value>CC BY</meta-value></custom-meta></custom-meta-group></article-meta></front><body><sec sec-type="intro" id="s1"><title>Introduction</title><p>The application of digital health technologies (DHTs) was expedited by the COVID-19 pandemic, and, to date, health care systems have become increasingly reliant on them [<xref rid="R1" ref-type="bibr">1</xref><xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>]. The integration of DHTs into health care has highlighted their potential to offer solutions to the significant pressures under which health care systems worldwide are operating [<xref rid="R3" ref-type="bibr">3</xref><xref rid="R4" ref-type="bibr">4</xref>]. Consequently, there is an increasing need to generate evidence to determine which interventions are the most beneficial and should be widely implemented, which is the last step in the eHealth evaluation cycle [<xref rid="R5" ref-type="bibr">5</xref><xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>]. One widely adopted instrument across countries for this is health technology assessment (HTA), which was originally developed to evaluate the effectiveness and economic value of nondigital health interventions (eg, pharmaceuticals) [<xref rid="R7" ref-type="bibr">7</xref>]. This instrument is also frequently used to inform decision-making for DHTs [<xref rid="R8" ref-type="bibr">8</xref><xref rid="R9" ref-type="bibr">9</xref>]. However, the health-related quality of life (QoL) and cost measures it includes do not completely capture the value of DHTs (including remote patient monitoring [RPM]) for different stakeholders, such as patients and health care providers [<xref rid="R10" ref-type="bibr">10</xref><xref rid="R11" ref-type="bibr">11</xref>].</p><p>The Quadruple Aim, which encompasses 4 health care goals (improved population health, improved patient and provider experience, and reduced costs), captures a broader value compared to HTA [<xref rid="R12" ref-type="bibr">12</xref>]. However, the existing literature does not examine all of these domains equally [<xref rid="R13" ref-type="bibr">13</xref><xref rid="R14" ref-type="bibr">14</xref>]. Additionally, the Quadruple Aim has expanded to include equity [<xref rid="R15" ref-type="bibr">15</xref>], a domain that is also highly relevant for DHTs [<xref rid="R16" ref-type="bibr">16</xref>]. A review emphasized the need for validated tools to quantitatively assess the impact of DHTs on equity [<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>]. This framework was further extended to the Sextuple Aim by incorporating sustainability, reflecting increasing concerns about the environmental impact of health care on population health [<xref rid="R18" ref-type="bibr">18</xref>]. Comprehensive evaluation across these domains alone is insufficient; it is also important to consider the needs of key stakeholders (eg, health care providers, managers, insurers) when evaluating DHTs because their needs and definitions of health care value differ [<xref rid="R19" ref-type="bibr">19</xref>]. Two recent Delphi studies incorporated the knowledge and perspectives of different stakeholders to develop a set of indicators for evaluating digital or virtual health technologies in a health care setting [<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref><xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>].</p><p>DHTs encompass a wide range of applications, including electronic health records, mobile health, telehealth, and RPM. RPM is a key driver of the rapid expansion of DHTs and uses information technologies to enable remote surveillance of patients by facilitating the transmission of clinical data between patients and health care providers [<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref><xref rid="R22" ref-type="bibr">22</xref>]. Moreover, RPM is distinguishable from other DHTs in that it involves active patient monitoring rather than passive monitoring and asynchronous patient-provider interaction [<xref rid="R23" ref-type="bibr">23</xref><xref rid="R24" ref-type="bibr">24</xref>]. Existing evaluation frameworks are more generic for DHTs or virtual health and may insufficiently capture these distinctive characteristics. Therefore, this study aims to identify the value aspects considered most important for assessing RPM interventions and to develop a multistakeholder core outcome set (COS) for RPM based on the Sextuple Aim. A modified Delphi design was chosen to iteratively build consensus among stakeholder groups, ensuring anonymity and independent judgments [<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>].</p></sec><sec sec-type="methods" id="s2"><title>Methods</title><sec id="s2-1"><title>Overview</title><p>To develop a COS, a combination of a literature search, one-on-one stakeholder meetings, 3 Delphi rounds, and a final expert meeting was conducted (<xref rid="F1" ref-type="fig">Figure 1</xref>). This design was guided by the COMET (Core Outcome Measures in Effectiveness Trials) initiative, recommending outcome identification (via literature searches), prioritization (eg, Delphi-based methods), and consensus meetings [<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Prior to the Delphi study, a literature search was conducted on reviews evaluating RPM interventions using (value) aspects of the Sextuple Aim (health, costs, patient experience, provider experience, equity, and sustainability) published in the last 10 years from 2016 to 2025 (<xref rid="SAP1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 1</xref>). Titles and abstracts of the reviews were independently screened by 2 reviewers and were eligible if they addressed 1 or more domains of the Sextuple Aim in the context of digital health. The full texts were then assessed, and potentially relevant value aspects were independently extracted by 2 researchers. Extracted aspects were discussed and consolidated to reach consensus. The preliminary list was further refined during meetings with experts, including patient representatives, health care providers, managers, insurers, and researchers. These experts were recruited through the researchers’ network. This process resulted in an initial list of 43 value aspects. More details on this process, along with an overview and their definitions, are presented in <xref rid="SAP2" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 2</xref>. These value aspects and their descriptions were incorporated into the Castor EDC online questionnaire tool for the first Delphi round (R1). For the second (R2) and third (R3) rounds, the online survey software tool Alchemer was used in order to conduct the ranking exercises. The findings of this study were reported in accordance with the ACCORD (Accurate Consensus Reporting Document) checklist (<xref rid="SCHL1" ref-type="supplementary-material">Checklist 1</xref>) [<xref rid="R26" ref-type="bibr">26</xref>].</p><fig position="float" id="F1" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 1.</label><caption><title> Schematic overview of the research process. R1: Round 1; R2: Round 2; R3: Round 3; ranking w. domains: ranking within Sextuple Aim domains; ranking a. domains: ranking across Sextuple Aim domains.</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-g001.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="s2-2"><title>Recruitment and Eligibility</title><p>Participants from 6 stakeholder groups involved in using or evaluating an RPM application in the care pathway were included: patients, informal caregivers or household members, health care providers, managers, insurers, and researchers. Recruitment occurred from March to April 2025. Respondents had to be fluent in Dutch and have experience with digital health applications. Patients and informal caregivers were recruited via the Dutch Patient Federation (Ikzoekeenpatiënt) [<xref rid="R27" ref-type="bibr">27</xref>]. The federation disseminated an invitation via its online platform, including a study description, eligibility criteria, and compensation for participation, and individuals could sign up. The federation ensured a diverse and representative sample of patients and informal caregivers with respect to age, sex, and health conditions. The other groups were recruited using snowball sampling, where initial participants from the researchers’ network were asked to participate and share the study invitation within their own networks. Recruitment channels included (1) online flyers distributed through stakeholder networks and LinkedIn and (2) direct outreach through hospital contacts. We aimed for 25 to 30 patients and informal caregivers per group, 20 to 30 health care providers, and 10 to 20 insurers, managers, and researchers in each group. The target sample size was at least 2-digit numbers per group, which was sufficient to support meaningful consensus [<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. The maximum target was 30 participants, as it is known that additional participants offer limited benefit and may reduce response rates [<xref rid="R29" ref-type="bibr">29</xref>]. Sample sizes per group were further aligned to balance diversity and feasibility.</p></sec><sec id="s2-3"><title>Pre-Delphi Steps</title><p>Before each Delphi round, the online questionnaire was piloted with laypeople to assess its clarity, perceived length, and ease of completion. The questionnaires were written in plain Dutch (Common European Framework of Reference for Languages B1), and value aspects were simplified (see <xref rid="SAP2" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 2</xref> for the original and simplified definitions) to ensure accessibility for all groups [<xref rid="R30" ref-type="bibr">30</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s2-4"><title>Delphi Procedure</title><p>Each Delphi round began with a project description. In R1, respondents were asked to rate the importance of each value aspect for evaluating the value of RPM interventions on a 5-point Likert scale, ranging from “unimportant” to “very important.” Respondents were encouraged to provide a rationale and comment on each aspect and report missing aspects. A “no opinion” option was included for each aspect, since not all aspects might be relevant to all stakeholder groups.</p><p>In R2, respondents first rerated the value aspects without consensus. They were provided with feedback (a graph showing the mean and frequency of the overall group and their stakeholder group, along with motivations). Respondents were also asked to rate the additional value aspects suggested in R1. Then, respondents ranked the value aspects within each domain from “most” (score=7 or a score equal to the number of value aspects within that domain) to “least” (score=1) important. For domains with more than 7 value aspects, respondents first selected the 7 they considered most important and then ranked them (unselected value aspects were assigned a score of 0). The items presented in the ranking exercise were randomized per domain for each respondent.</p><p>In R3, respondents rerated the value aspects without consensus and received comparable feedback as in R2. Then, respondents selected and ranked the 10 most important aspects across all domains from most (score=10) to least (score=1) important (unselected value aspects were assigned a score of 0). Again, the order of items was randomized.</p><p>To encourage timely questionnaire completion and increase response rates, reminders were sent out twice for each round (every 2 weeks), except for insurers, who received a third reminder for R2 [<xref rid="R31" ref-type="bibr">31</xref>]. To reduce group pressure and conformity bias, anonymity was ensured [<xref rid="R32" ref-type="bibr">32</xref><xref rid="R33" ref-type="bibr">33</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s2-5"><title>Data Analysis and Selection Criteria</title><p>The anonymized data were analyzed using SPSS software (version 29; IBM Corp). The results of the Delphi ratings were analyzed by calculating percentages and IQRs. To analyze the overall group rating results, these metrics were weighted to account for different group sizes. The IQR represented the distance between the 25th and 75th percentile values in the rating (a smaller IQR represented greater consensus). Consensus on importance was reached when at least 75% of respondents (excluding those with “no opinion”) rated a value aspect as “important” or “very important,” and the IQR was ≤1. Both metrics were used to ensure high agreement and limited dispersion [<xref rid="R34" ref-type="bibr">34</xref>]. Similarly, consensus of unimportance was defined as at least 75% of participants rating a value aspect as “unimportant” or “somewhat important” together with an IQR ≤1. If no consensus was reached, the value aspect was rerated in the subsequent round. To analyze the ranking results of value aspects within domains, mean rank scores were normalized to a common scale ranging from 0 to 100 for each stakeholder group (<xref rid="SAP3" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 3</xref>). This normalization accounted for differences in the number of value aspects per domain, ensuring comparability across domains. Higher normalized ranking scores indicated a higher relative priority within that domain. To calculate the overall ranking within the domains, the normalized scores were weighted by stakeholder group size. Complete-case sensitivity analyses assessed the impact of respondent retention within and between groups on the rated importance and ranking within domains of value aspects. The ratings and rankings within domains for respondents who completed all 3 rounds were analyzed similarly to the full sample, and the results were compared.</p><p>In the overall ranking across domains, respondents selected and then ranked the 10 value aspects. Mean ranks were calculated for each group, as well as an overall weighted mean. In a sensitivity analysis, the unselected aspects were assigned a negative score of −10 to replace the assumption of neutrality with active deprioritization. This value was chosen to generate the largest possible separation from the selected and ranked aspects (scored 1‐10) while remaining within the ranking ranges.</p><p>A multicriteria consensus rule was used to select value aspects for a preliminary COS. These criteria were derived from the literature and input from experts [<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref><xref rid="R35" ref-type="bibr">35</xref>]. This a priori defined rule combined rating and ranking results to integrate absolute importance and relative prioritization. Value aspects were included in the COS if they met 2 of the following criteria: (1) rated as “important” or “very important” by ≥75% of respondents and IQR ≤1 (the importance-consensus criterion); (2) the mean ranking was higher than or equal to that in a hypothetical situation in which all value aspects within the domain were considered equally important (the ranking within domains criterion); and (3) the weighted mean of the overall ranking was in the top 25 (the ranking across domains criterion).</p></sec><sec id="s2-6"><title>Expert Meeting</title><p>Following the Delphi rounds, consensus on the COS was reached at a 3-hour expert meeting held in September 2025. We aimed to recruit 10 experts, purposively sampled to ensure representation from various stakeholder groups while maintaining a manageable group size that would facilitate in-depth discussion and promote equal contributions. Due to scheduling constraints, 7 experts participated: 3 researchers, 2 managers, 1 provider, and 1 patient or informal caregiver representative from the Dutch Patient Federation. Three of the 7 experts had also participated in the Delphi study, providing continuity with the previous rounds while also ensuring independent perspectives, thereby reducing overreliance on prior outcomes. Despite multiple recruitment attempts, no insurer was able to attend this meeting; therefore, the insurer perspective was only represented in the Delphi results. During the meeting, 2 subgroups were formed to ensure balanced representation within each one. One subgroup consisted of 2 researchers (1 of whom had clinical experience), a manager, and a patient representative, while the other subgroup comprised a researcher, a health care provider, and a manager. The experts first received written and verbal summaries of the rating and ranking results. The subgroups were then tasked with proposing a COS based on the preliminary COS derived from the predefined multicriteria consensus rule. Discussions were guided by the results of the Delphi rounds, and any discrepancies were addressed in a moderated discussion. The moderator, a member of the research team with expertise in evaluating interventions and developing outcome measures, ensured equal participation and had no direct interest in the outcomes. To minimize moderator-induced bias, the moderator’s role was limited to facilitating discussion and summarizing findings, in accordance with the COMET guidelines [<xref rid="R25" ref-type="bibr">25</xref>]. Proposed changes to the COS were discussed until a unanimous decision was reached. Through this iterative, moderated process, a final COS was agreed upon.</p></sec><sec id="s2-7"><title>Ethical Considerations</title><p>The Leiden University Medical Center’s non–<italic toggle="yes">Wet Medisch-Wetenschappelijk Onderzoek</italic> committee approved the study. The committee deemed the study not subject to the Dutch Medical Research Involving Human Subjects Act (nWMO-D4-2024-018). All participants received written information about the study’s objectives and anticipated benefits. For patients and informal caregivers, the information was written in plain Dutch (Common European Framework of Reference for Languages B1). All participants provided informed consent before enrolling in the study (<xref rid="SAP4" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 4</xref>). Participation was voluntary, and participants could withdraw at any time without consequence. Patients and informal caregivers received a €25 gift (US $29.30, averaged exchange rate in September 2025) card after completing all 3 rounds. External experts participating in the expert meeting were reimbursed for their time and travel expenses but received no direct financial incentives for participation. Before analyzing the data, patient-identifying information and anonymized study data were separated. The patient-identifying information was saved on a separate disk, which was only accessible to the 2 main researchers.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="results" id="s3"><title>Results</title><sec id="s3-1"><title>Delphi Participants</title><p>The demographics of the participants in the different stakeholder groups are described in <xref rid="T1" ref-type="table">Table 1</xref>. A total of 171 participants completed R1, of whom 148 (87%) completed R2 and 137 (80%) completed R3. Retention rates varied among the groups, ranging from 97% for patients to 50% for insurers.</p><table-wrap position="float" id="T1" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 1.</label><caption><title> Characteristics of participants in the Delphi study.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Participants</th><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Participants in R1<xref rid="T1_FN1" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>a</sup></xref> (N=171), n (%)</th><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Participants in R2<xref rid="T1_FN2" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>b</sup></xref>, n (%)</th><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Participants in R3<xref rid="T1_FN3" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>c</sup></xref>, n (%)</th><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Age in R1 (y), mean (SD)</th><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Women in R1, n (%)</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Patients</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58 (33.9)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56 (97)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56 (97)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">63.4 (11.1)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">32 (55)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Informal caregivers</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45 (26.3)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40 (89)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37 (82)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">65.0 (12.1)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29 (64)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Health care providers</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">27 (15.8)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">18 (67)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">15 (56)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42.5 (10.3)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17 (63)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Health care managers</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">23 (13.5)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">19 (83)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17 (74)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44.7 (11)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">17 (74)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Health care insurers</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">8 (4.7)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">5 (63)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">4 (50)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">44.9 (13)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">3 (38)</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Researchers</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (5.8)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">10 (100)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">9 (90)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">31.9 (4.9)</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">7 (70)</td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="T1_FN1" fn-type="other"><label>a</label><p>R1: round 1.</p></fn><fn id="T1_FN2" fn-type="other"><label>b</label><p>R2: round 2.</p></fn><fn id="T1_FN3" fn-type="other"><label>c</label><p>R3: round 3.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap></sec><sec id="s3-2"><title>Results of Weighted Rating</title><p>The rating of value aspects was conducted in all 3 rounds. In R2 and R3, aspects for which no consensus had been reached were rerated. In R1, respondents rated the initial set of 43 value aspects derived from the literature review and meetings with experts (<xref rid="F2" ref-type="fig">Figure 2</xref>). In R1, for 31 value aspects, consensus on importance was met, as the rated importance was ≥75% and the IQR was ≤1 (<xref rid="T2" ref-type="table">Table 2</xref>). None of the aspects met the unimportance-consensus criterion. All aspects within the health, equity, and provider experience domains met the importance-consensus criterion. Twelve value aspects did not meet consensus on either criterion for importance or unimportance and, hence, had to be rerated in the subsequent round: 3 from the patient experience domain, the sustainability value aspect, and 8 from the cost domain. Managers were the only stakeholder group for which “sustainability” met the importance-consensus criterion. See <xref rid="SAP5" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 5</xref> for the distribution of the value aspects lacking consensus across groups.</p><fig position="float" id="F2" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 2.</label><caption><title>All group mean weighted rating of value aspects in the 3 rounds of the Delphi study; bar shading denotes the rating round: lighter bars represent aspects rerated in later rounds (R2 or R3) due to lack of prior consensus or because they were newly introduced in R2. [X] indicates the round in which an aspect was introduced. inf.: informal; QoC: quality of care; QoL: quality of life.</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-g002.jpg"/></fig><table-wrap position="float" id="T2" orientation="portrait"><label>Table 2.</label><caption><title>Heatmap of final percentage perceived importance (“important” or “very important”) and IQR.</title></caption><table frame="hsides" rules="groups"><thead><tr><th valign="bottom" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Value aspect [final round rated]<xref rid="T2_FN5" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>a</sup></xref></th><th colspan="7" valign="bottom" rowspan="1">Final percentage perceived importance (IQR)<xref rid="T2_FN6" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>b</sup></xref></th></tr><tr><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"/><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Overall<xref rid="T2_FN1" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>c</sup></xref></th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Patient</th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Caregiver</th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Provider</th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Manager</th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Insurer</th><th align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">Researcher</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Patient experience</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Patient satisfaction [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Access to care [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Information provision [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.3 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Therapy adherence [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Communication provider [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Patient involvement [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Perceived safety [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Ease of use technology [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Impact treatment [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">84.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Self-control [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">79.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Health knowledge [2]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">84.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.8 (0.2)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Self-management [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">83.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Technology adherence [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">83.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Uncertainty measurements [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">73.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48.2 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">61.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.6 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Social system [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">73.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">72.7 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Social contact [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58.7 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">67.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">53.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Travel burden [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.3 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">48.2 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58.4 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.4 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">47.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Health</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> QoL<xref rid="T2_FN2" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>k</sup></xref> patients [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.2 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.8 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Health outcomes [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> QoL informal caregiver [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">78.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">76.2 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (3.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">55.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Equity</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Equality across groups [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited physical abilities [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96.5 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited financial resources [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.4 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.5 (0.3)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited literacy [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">94.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited health literacy [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited digital skills [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">92.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Limited health care location [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">79.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.3 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (2.5)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Costs</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Health care costs [2]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">61.1 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.5 (0.2)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Productivity provider [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">76.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">66.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Health care use [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">76.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">73.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">77.2 (0.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">55.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Out-of-pocket costs [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">69.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">68.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">53.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">76.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Costs health insurer [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46.5 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Productivity informal caregiver [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">59.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.6 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Monitoring costs [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">58.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.7 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Productivity patient [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40.4 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Travel costs [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (2.8)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41.2 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">37.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Costs outside of health care [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">39.6 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">46.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">35.3 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">42.9 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Provider experience</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> QoC<xref rid="T2_FN3" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>l</sup></xref> [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.7 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">97.7 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">96.3 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Patient involvement [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">89.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Workload [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">100.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Provider satisfaction [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">84.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Ease of use technology [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">86.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.9 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">82.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">75.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">90.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Communication patient [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">98.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">93.2 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">88.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">91.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">71.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">70.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Acceptance technology [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">85.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">81.4 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">95.6 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">87.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN15" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>d</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">80.0 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td colspan="8" align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1">Sustainability</td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Sustainability [1]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">60.2 (1.3)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">51.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">57.8 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">68.1 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">79.1 (0.3)<xref rid="T2_FN14" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>f</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">45.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">33.3 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Reusability equipment [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">57.0 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">54.6 (3.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">56.7 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">53.3 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">64.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">50.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN12" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>g</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">62.5 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN13" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>e</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Pollution travel [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">30.8 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">38.1 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40.5 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">40.0 (2.0)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">41.2 (1.5)<xref rid="T2_FN11" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>h</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.0 (0.8)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">25.0 (1.8)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td></tr><tr><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1"> Energy use [3]</td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">13.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN9" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>m</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">29.1 (3.0)<xref rid="T2_FN10" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>i</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">22.2 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN9" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>m</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">6.7 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">11.8 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">0.0 (0.0)<xref rid="T2_FN8" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>j</sup></xref></td><td align="left" valign="top" rowspan="1" colspan="1">12.5 (1.0)<xref rid="T2_FN9" ref-type="table-fn"><sup>m</sup></xref></td></tr></tbody></table><table-wrap-foot><fn id="T2_FN5" fn-type="other"><label>a</label><p>[Final round rated]: the last round in which a value aspect was rated; when consensus was reached, it was not rerated in the subsequent round.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN6" fn-type="other"><label>b</label><p>Final percentage perceived importance (IQR): the percentage perceived importance and IQR for an aspect as rated in the last round an aspect was (re)rated.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN1" fn-type="other"><label>c</label><p>Results were weighted to correct for differences in sample size. </p></fn><fn id="T2_FN15" fn-type="other"><label>d</label><p>Sample size: ≥87.5 to 100.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN13" fn-type="other"><label>e</label><p>Sample size: ≥62.5 to &lt;75.0.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN14" fn-type="other"><label>f</label><p>Sample size: ≥75.0 to &lt;87.5.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN12" fn-type="other"><label>g</label><p>Sample size: ≥50.0 to &lt;62.5.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN11" fn-type="other"><label>h</label><p>Sample size: ≥37.5 to &lt;50.0.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN10" fn-type="other"><label>i</label><p>Sample size: ≥25.0 to &lt;37.5.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN8" fn-type="other"><label>j</label><p>Sample size: ≥0.0 to &lt;12.5.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN2" fn-type="other"><label>k</label><p>QoL: quality of life.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN3" fn-type="other"><label>l</label><p>QoC: quality of care.</p></fn><fn id="T2_FN9" fn-type="other"><label>m</label><p>Sample size: ≥12.5 to &lt;25.0.</p></fn></table-wrap-foot></table-wrap><p>Respondents’ suggestions led to the addition of the aspects “social system” and “uncertainty from measurements” to the patient experience domain. Additionally, suggestions within the sustainability domain resulted in the value aspect “sustainability” being split into 3.</p><p>After R2, the aspects “health knowledge” and “health care costs” met the importance-consensus criterion. The remaining 14 aspects were rerated in R3. In R3, these aspects were perceived as less important than in R2 and did not meet the consensus criteria for importance or unimportance. Ultimately, 33 of 47 (70%) aspects met the importance-consensus criterion. Consensus was least often achieved in the sustainability domain, where all 3 value aspects (100%) fell below the threshold, followed by the cost domain (7 aspects, 70%), and, to a lesser extent, the patient experience domain (4 aspects, 24%). Divergence was observed between stakeholder groups regarding the importance of value aspects within the cost domain. Managers and the small group of insurers rated 6 and 5 value aspects as important, respectively, while the other stakeholder groups rated 1 (the researcher group) or at most 3 value aspects (the provider group) as important.</p><p>The “no opinion” option was infrequently selected across rounds, with patients using this option more often than other stakeholder groups (<xref rid="SAP6" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 6</xref>).</p></sec><sec id="s3-3"><title>Results of Weighted Ranking Within Domains</title><p>The ranking of value aspects within each domain reflects their relative prioritization (<xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>). Across domains, approximately half of the value aspects were prioritized above the domain average, which provided differentiation in relative importance. Value aspects scoring above the domain average (ie, the expected score if all aspects were equally ranked) are above the reference line (<xref rid="F3" ref-type="fig">Figure 3</xref>). According to this ranking, 25 of 47 (53%) aspects were ranked above average and, hence, met the ranking within domains criterion. See <xref rid="SAP7" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 7</xref> for the ranking of the aspects within domains by the individual stakeholder groups. No remarkable differences were found among the stakeholder groups.</p><fig position="float" id="F3" fig-type="figure" orientation="portrait"><label>Figure 3.</label><caption><title>All groups normalized (weighted) mean rankings within domains; the orange line represents the average value if all value aspects had been ranked equally. inf.: informal; Meas.: measurement; QoC: quality of care; QoL: quality of life.</title></caption><graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" position="float" orientation="portrait" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-g003.jpg"/></fig></sec><sec id="s3-4"><title>Results of Weighted Ranking Across Domains</title><p>The ranking across domains exercise examined the relative priority of value aspects across all domains. Overall, the across-domain ranking showed that value aspects within the health, provider experience, patient experience, and equity domains were most frequently prioritized, whereas aspects from the cost domain were less often selected among the highest-ranked aspects. Value aspects met the ranking across domains criterion if they were in the overall top 25. The top 25 value aspects across domains included all health aspects (3/3), the majority of provider experience aspects (6/7), more than half of patient experience aspects (10/17) and equity aspects (4/7), and a limited number of cost aspects (2/10; <xref rid="SAP8" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 8</xref>). The 10 highest-ranked value aspects of each group were incorporated into the overall top 25, except for “out-of-pocket costs,” which was in the patients’ top 10 but not in the overall top 25. All stakeholder groups included “patient QoL” and “quality of care (QoC)” in their top 10. All groups except managers ranked “patient QoL” as number 1, whereas managers ranked it third and “QoC” as first.</p><p>The sensitivity analysis (deprioritization instead of neutrality) only minorly changed the top 25 value aspects included (<xref rid="SAP9" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 9</xref>). Within the top 25, “limited financial resources” was removed from the top 25 (from 25th to 27th place), while “information provision” was added (from 26th to 24th place).</p></sec><sec id="s3-5"><title>Multicriteria Consensus Rule and Expert Meeting</title><p>Following the multicriteria consensus rule, the preliminary COS included 26 value aspects. Twenty-one (81%) aspects met all 3 criteria (<xref rid="SAP10" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 10</xref>). All of the value aspects in the preliminary COS met the importance-consensus criterion. Of the 5 (19%) aspects meeting only 2 criteria, 4 did not meet the ranking within domains criterion, and 1 did not meet the ranking across domains criterion. The complete-case sensitivity analyses revealed no discrepancies in the value aspects that met the importance-consensus criterion and the within-domains ranking of value aspects (<xref rid="SAP11" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 11</xref>), as the same aspects were retained in the preliminary COS.</p><p>During the expert meeting, the subgroups created a COS informed by the results of the ratings and rankings. The subgroup outputs were then discussed in a moderated plenary session, where value aspects were merged, removed, or relocated when consensus was reached. Value aspects were merged when they were considered to be conceptually overlapping and thus reflected the same underlying construct. This was identified among aspects within the patient experience, cost, and provider experience domains (<xref rid="B1" ref-type="boxed-text">Textbox 1</xref>). These were combined into 3 paired value aspects. For instance, the aspects “patient involvement” and “communication with patients” within the provider experience domain were merged, as the experts indicated that meaningful communication with patients is grounded in patient involvement. Value aspects were removed when they were judged to represent outcomes arising from other included aspects rather than standalone values. For instance, “patient satisfaction” was removed from the patient experience domain because it was viewed as the cumulative result of other patient experience aspects and may depend more on a patient’s momentary mood than on their experience with the RPM intervention [<xref rid="R36" ref-type="bibr">36</xref>]. Relocation occurred when an aspect aligned more closely with a different Sextuple Aim domain based on its meaning. “Access to care” was relocated from the patient experience domain and merged with 5 aspects from the equity domain and added to it because these aspects were considered fundamental to access. “Sustainability” did not meet the multicriteria consensus rule, but its emergent relevance for the long-term viability of health care systems was acknowledged during the expert meeting. Following this, sustainability was included as a recommended value aspect in the COS.</p><boxed-text id="B1" position="float" orientation="portrait"><label>Textbox 1.</label><caption><title>Core outcome set based on Delphi results and expert meeting.</title></caption><p>
<bold>Patient experience</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Self-control</p></list-item><list-item><p>Self-management</p></list-item><list-item><p>Impact on treatment and life</p></list-item><list-item><p>Therapy adherence</p></list-item><list-item><p>Patient involvement</p></list-item><list-item><p>Ease of use of technology</p></list-item><list-item><p>Perceived safety</p></list-item><list-item><p>Communication with provider</p></list-item></list><p>
<bold>Health</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Quality of life, patient</p></list-item><list-item><p>Health outcomes</p></list-item><list-item><p>Quality of life, informal caregiver</p></list-item></list><p>
<bold>Provider experience</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Experienced quality of care</p></list-item><list-item><p>Workload</p></list-item><list-item><p>Communication with patient</p></list-item></list><p>
<bold>Equity</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Access to care (health literacy, financial resources, physical abilities, digital skills, and equality across groups)</p></list-item></list><p>
<bold>Costs</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Health care costs</p></list-item><list-item><p>Provider productivity</p></list-item></list><p>
<bold>Sustainability</bold>
</p><list list-type="bullet" list-content="ul"><list-item><p>Sustainability (included as a recommended value aspect rather than a required value aspect)</p></list-item></list></boxed-text></sec></sec><sec sec-type="discussion" id="s4"><title>Discussion</title><sec id="s4-1"><title>Principal Findings</title><p>Applying the multicriteria consensus rule to the Delphi results and subsequent expert meeting yielded a final RPM Sextuple Aim COS comprising 17 value aspects and 1 recommended aspect. This COS extends beyond traditional HTA domains, incorporating value aspects from the cost and health domains as well as 12 aspects from the patient experience, provider experience, and equity domains. This emphasizes that the value of RPM interventions is reflected in broader dimensions. Notably, no value aspects within the sustainability domain met the multicriteria consensus rule. However, during the expert meeting, experts recommended including sustainability as a value aspect in the final COS, as there was consensus on its emergent relevance for the long-term viability of health care systems.</p><p>Notable differences were observed between stakeholder groups for value aspects within the cost domain. Managers and the small group of insurers consistently rated these value aspects as more important than other stakeholder groups. These findings are supported by a previous study, which observed that the importance of costs when evaluating an intervention depends on the stakeholder group, with costs also being considered more important by managers and insurers than by health care providers [<xref rid="R37" ref-type="bibr">37</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s4-2"><title>Comparison With Prior Work</title><p>Two previous multistakeholder Delphi studies have established sets of items for evaluating DHTs and virtual care, using the Quadruple Aim and Quintuple Aim, respectively [<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref><xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>]. Our research contributes to current knowledge by specifically focusing on RPM, the largest contributor to the expansion of DHTs [<xref rid="R21" ref-type="bibr">21</xref>]. Petrie et al [<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] identified similar items (within provider experiences: eg, QoC and workload) but also reported different items. In this study, we explicitly included aspects belonging to the effectiveness and uptake phases of the eHealth evaluation cycle (eg, communication with providers), whereas Petrie et al [<xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>] also incorporated items related to earlier phases (eg, interoperability and portability) [<xref rid="R6" ref-type="bibr">6</xref>].</p><p>Although Haig et al [<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref>] addressed the Quadruple Aim, they also included a sustainability item on which no consensus was reached. This finding aligns with the results of this study. Although studies show that environmental sustainability is increasingly viewed as important among stakeholder groups, it is still rarely incorporated into health care decision-making [<xref rid="R38" ref-type="bibr">38</xref><xref rid="R39" ref-type="bibr">39</xref>]. This was also observed in decisions regarding the adoption of telemonitoring [<xref rid="R40" ref-type="bibr">40</xref>]. One possible explanation for this discrepancy may be that the necessary expertise, metrics, and practical tools needed to account for environmental impacts are still emerging and have not yet been embedded in routine assessment and decision-making processes. The same holds for equity. A recent literature review revealed that equity is rarely assessed in RPM research, which underscores the need for a validated tool to quantitatively assess this dimension [<xref rid="R17" ref-type="bibr">17</xref>].</p><p>The interpretability, coherence, and comprehensiveness of the final COS were ensured at the expert meeting, where the findings of the Delphi rounds were discussed, and conceptually overlapping value aspects were merged [<xref rid="R41" ref-type="bibr">41</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s4-3"><title>Limitations</title><p>This study has limitations. First, we aimed to include 10 to 20 insurers and researchers based on availability and feasibility. However, only 8 insurers participated in R1, meaning that the aim was not met, and the insurer perspective was underrepresented relative to the other stakeholder groups. This may have been offset by weighting the results by stakeholder group. Second, although the retention rate was comparable to or higher than that of previous digital-application Delphi studies [<xref rid="R2" ref-type="bibr">2</xref><xref rid="R20" ref-type="bibr">20</xref>], attrition was substantial in the insurer group, where only half of the initial participants completed R3. To assess the potential impact of this dropout, we conducted a sensitivity analysis including only respondents who completed all 3 rounds. These complete-case analyses showed no meaningful changes in the results of rating and within-domain ranking (<xref rid="SAP11" ref-type="supplementary-material">Multimedia Appendix 11</xref>): the same value aspects were retained in the preliminary COS, suggesting that participants who discontinued had similar views to those who completed all rounds. Third, the composition of the expert meeting differed from that of the Delphi process, with a higher proportion of researchers present and no insurer representation. As this meeting was used to finalize the COS, the imbalance in stakeholder representation may have influenced the final prioritization decisions. Although discussions were moderated and structured to encourage equal participation, imbalances in the composition of expert groups and the absence of key stakeholder perspectives are recognized challenges in Delphi studies [<xref rid="R28" ref-type="bibr">28</xref>]. Fourth, the definitions of value aspects were simplified to ensure clarity and comprehensibility for all respondents. While this approach facilitated broader understanding and engagement, it may have slightly altered the scientific definition. For example, the definition of self-management focused on perceived control and ability to act, lacking the skill development aspect of the scientific definition [<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>]. Consequently, the importance attributed to certain value aspects might have differed if the scientific definition had been used. Even though simplified language was used in the Delphi rounds and the Dutch Patient Federation facilitated participant recruitment, including individuals with low literacy was not a goal of this study and remains a challenge [<xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Those with limited literacy may struggle with text-heavy questionnaires and abstract concepts, potentially introducing selection bias [<xref rid="R43" ref-type="bibr">43</xref>]. Selection bias could also arise from the snowball sampling recruitment approach used, which may have led to an overrepresentation of individuals more interested in or engaged with RPM. This could have influenced the prioritization of value aspects. Fifth, rating aspects is prone to agreement bias and nondifferentiation, with respondents tending to answer positively and show less variation [<xref rid="R44" ref-type="bibr">44</xref>]. The ratings indicate that 33 of 47 aspects would have been retained. To mitigate this tendency and encourage stronger discrimination between value aspects, we therefore also included ranking exercises. Lastly, this Delphi study was conducted within the Dutch health care context, which may limit the generalizability of the findings to other health care systems. Characteristics of the Dutch setting, such as short travel distances and its reimbursement structure, may have influenced the rating and ranking of value aspects, particularly those related to travel, access, and costs.</p></sec><sec id="s4-4"><title>Future Directions</title><p>The primary focus of this COS was to support HTA in improving existing evaluation tools used for telemonitoring, thereby supporting policy decision-making [<xref rid="R45" ref-type="bibr">45-47</xref>]. By systematically comparing existing tools with the COS, missing value aspects can be identified and incorporated, resulting in validated and comprehensive evaluation tools for assessing RPM interventions. This COS may be applied in broader terms, for example, by operationalizing its value aspects into measurable items to create an evaluation tool that can inform organizational and clinical decision-making, especially in the effectiveness and uptake phases of RPM development, where these aspects can be repeatedly assessed to capture evolving value. Future studies may focus on operationalizing and subsequently validating the COS. Another important direction for future research is the incorporation of perspectives from patients with limited (health) literacy. This inclusion would enhance the societal applicability of the COS, especially given concerns that the ongoing digital transformation may inadvertently increase the burden of health management on patients, potentially risking the widening of health disparities rather than promoting equity [<xref rid="R42" ref-type="bibr">42</xref>].</p></sec><sec id="s4-5"><title>Conclusions</title><p>This Delphi study constituted an RPM Sextuple Aim COS comprising 17 value aspects and 1 recommended value aspect, providing a multidimensional and multistakeholder evaluation set. This COS provides a standardized and comprehensive basis for evaluating and comparing RPM interventions and can be used to support the validation and refinement of existing RPM evaluation tools. Future research may consider operationalizing the COS and its recommended aspect into measurable items and assessing its feasibility and uptake in practice.</p></sec></sec><sec sec-type="supplementary-material" id="s5"><title>Supplementary material</title><supplementary-material id="SAP1" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 1</label><caption><title>Search strategy.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s001.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 16 KB" id="d69e2347" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP2" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 2</label><caption><title>Overview value aspects.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s002.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 25 KB" id="d69e2354" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP3" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 3</label><caption><title>Calculation normalization ranking across domains.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s003.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 14 KB" id="d69e2361" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP4" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 4</label><caption><title>Informed consent waiver.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s004.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 15 KB" id="d69e2368" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP5" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 5</label><caption><title>Value aspects without consensus.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s005.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 35 KB" id="d69e2375" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP6" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 6</label><caption><title>Attrition across rounds.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s006.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 24 KB" id="d69e2382" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP7" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 7</label><caption><title>Table normalized mean rankings.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s007.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 26 KB" id="d69e2389" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP8" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 8</label><caption><title>Table ranking across domains.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s008.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 32 KB" id="d69e2396" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP9" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 9</label><caption><title>Sensitivity analysis deprioritization.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s009.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 22 KB" id="d69e2403" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP10" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 10</label><caption><title>Preliminary core outcome set.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s010.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 17 KB" id="d69e2410" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SAP11" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Multimedia Appendix 11</label><caption><title>Complete-case sensitivity analyses.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s011.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 24 KB" id="d69e2418" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material><supplementary-material id="SCHL1" position="float" content-type="local-data" orientation="portrait"><object-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/92863</object-id><label>Checklist 1</label><caption><title>ACCORD checklist.</title></caption><media xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="jmir-v28-e92863-s012.docx" xlink:title="DOCX File, 99 KB" id="d69e2425" position="anchor" orientation="portrait"/></supplementary-material></sec></body><back><ack><title>Acknowledgments</title><p>During the preparation of this work, the authors used Microsoft Copilot 365 to improve the readability and language of the manuscript. After using this tool, the authors reviewed and edited the content and took full responsibility for the publication.</p></ack><fn-group><fn fn-type="financial-disclosure"><p><bold>Funding:</bold> This research was funded by the Netherlands Organization for Health Research and Development (ZonMw Netherlands), project number 10580012310007. The funding body had no role in the analysis or the writing of the manuscript.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Data Availability:</bold> The datasets generated or analyzed during this study are available from the corresponding author on reasonable request.</p></fn><fn fn-type="other"><p><bold>Authors’ Contributions:</bold> AH wrote the manuscript and conducted the Delphi study. TB and KR helped interpret the data. MEvdA-vM reviewed early versions of the manuscript and helped conduct and analyze the Delphi study. All authors reviewed the final manuscript.</p></fn><fn fn-type="COI-statement"><p><bold>Conflicts of Interest:</bold> None declared.</p></fn></fn-group><notes><def-list><title>Abbreviations</title><def-item><term>ACCORD</term><def><p>Accurate Consensus Reporting Document</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>COMET</term><def><p>Core Outcome Measures in Effectiveness Trials</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>COS</term><def><p>core outcome set</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>DHT</term><def><p> digital health tool</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>HTA</term><def><p>health technology assessment</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>QoC</term><def><p>quality of care</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>QoL</term><def><p>quality of life</p></def></def-item><def-item><term>RPM </term><def><p>remote patient monitoring</p></def></def-item></def-list></notes><ref-list><title>References</title><ref id="R1"><label>1.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Serrano</surname><given-names>LP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Maita</surname><given-names>KC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Avila</surname><given-names>FR</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Benefits and challenges of remote patient monitoring as perceived by health care practitioners: a systematic review</article-title><source>Perm J</source><month>Dec</month><day>15</day><year>2023</year><volume>27</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>100</fpage><lpage>111</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7812/TPP/23.022</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37735970</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10730976</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R2"><label>2.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Haig</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Main</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chávez</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kanavos</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>A value framework to assess patient-facing digital health technologies that aim to improve chronic disease management: a Delphi approach</article-title><source>Value Health</source><month>Oct</month><year>2023</year><volume>26</volume><issue>10</issue><fpage>1474</fpage><lpage>1484</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2023.06.008</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37385445</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R3"><label>3.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Khan</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The emerging challenges and strengths of the National Health Services: a physician perspective</article-title><source>Cureus</source><month>05</month><year>2023</year><volume>15</volume><issue>5</issue><elocation-id>e38617</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.7759/cureus.38617</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37284412</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10240167</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R4"><label>4.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Senbekov</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Saliev</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bukeyeva</surname><given-names>Z</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>The recent progress and applications of digital technologies in healthcare: a review</article-title><source>Int J Telemed Appl</source><year>2020</year><volume>2020</volume><elocation-id>8830200</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1155/2020/8830200</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">33343657</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7732404</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R5"><label>5.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Narayan</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Adashi</surname><given-names>EY</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The future of remote patient monitoring</article-title><source>J Gen Intern Med</source><month>Sep</month><year>2025</year><volume>40</volume><issue>13</issue><fpage>3207</fpage><lpage>3209</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11606-025-09552-0</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40329032</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12508345</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R6"><label>6.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rauwerdink</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Spinazze</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gijsbers</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Approaches to evaluating digital health technologies: scoping review</article-title><source>J Med Internet Res</source><month>Aug</month><day>28</day><year>2024</year><volume>26</volume><elocation-id>e50251</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/50251</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39196643</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11391152</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R7"><label>7.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Enzing</surname><given-names>JJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Knies</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Boer</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brouwer</surname><given-names>WBF</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Broadening the application of health technology assessment in the Netherlands: a worthwhile destination but not an easy ride?</article-title><source>Health Econ Policy Law</source><month>Oct</month><year>2021</year><volume>16</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>440</fpage><lpage>456</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1017/S1744133120000237</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32758331</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8460451</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R8"><label>8.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hofmann</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Branner</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Misra</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lintener</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>A review of current approaches to defining and valuing innovation in health technology assessment</article-title><source>Value Health</source><month>Dec</month><year>2021</year><volume>24</volume><issue>12</issue><fpage>1773</fpage><lpage>1783</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jval.2021.06.006</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34838275</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R9"><label>9.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Vis</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bührmann</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Riper</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ossebaard</surname><given-names>HC</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Health technology assessment frameworks for eHealth: a systematic review</article-title><source>Int J Technol Assess Health Care</source><month>Jun</month><year>2020</year><volume>36</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>204</fpage><lpage>216</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1017/S026646232000015X</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32297588</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R10"><label>10.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Seixas</surname><given-names>BV</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Dionne</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Conte</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mitton</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Assessing value in health care: using an interpretive classification system to understand existing practices based on a systematic review</article-title><source>BMC Health Serv Res</source><month>Aug</month><day>13</day><year>2019</year><volume>19</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>560</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12913-019-4405-6</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31409369</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6693163</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R11"><label>11.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gomes</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Murray</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Raftery</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Economic evaluation of digital health interventions: methodological issues and recommendations for practice</article-title><source>Pharmacoeconomics</source><month>Apr</month><year>2022</year><volume>40</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>367</fpage><lpage>378</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s40273-022-01130-0</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35132606</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8821841</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R12"><label>12.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Canfell</surname><given-names>OJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Woods</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Meshkat</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>The impact of digital hospitals on patient and clinician experience: systematic review and qualitative evidence synthesis</article-title><source>J Med Internet Res</source><month>Mar</month><day>11</day><year>2024</year><volume>26</volume><elocation-id>e47715</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/47715</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38466978</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10964148</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R13"><label>13.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Petrie</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Laur</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rios</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Quality measures of virtual care in ambulatory healthcare environments: a scoping review</article-title><source>BMJ Open</source><month>Apr</month><day>2</day><year>2024</year><volume>14</volume><issue>4</issue><elocation-id>e078214</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2023-078214</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38569716</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10989112</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R14"><label>14.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Culmer</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Smith</surname><given-names>TB</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Stager</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Asynchronous telemedicine: a systematic literature review</article-title><source>Telemed Rep</source><year>2023</year><volume>4</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>366</fpage><lpage>386</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1089/tmr.2023.0052</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38143795</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10739789</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R15"><label>15.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Nundy</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cooper</surname><given-names>LA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mate</surname><given-names>KS</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The quintuple aim for health care improvement: a new imperative to advance health equity</article-title><source>JAMA</source><month>Feb</month><day>8</day><year>2022</year><volume>327</volume><issue>6</issue><fpage>521</fpage><lpage>522</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.25181</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35061006</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R16"><label>16.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lyles</surname><given-names>CR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wachter</surname><given-names>RM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sarkar</surname><given-names>U</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Focusing on digital health equity</article-title><source>JAMA</source><month>Nov</month><day>9</day><year>2021</year><volume>326</volume><issue>18</issue><fpage>1795</fpage><lpage>1796</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1001/jama.2021.18459</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">34677577</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R17"><label>17.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Abejirinde</surname><given-names>IOO</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kishimoto</surname><given-names>V</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pfisterer</surname><given-names>KJ</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>An equity analysis of remote patient monitoring programs unveils assumptions on digital health equity</article-title><source>NPJ Digit Med</source><month>05</month><day>29</day><year>2025</year><volume>8</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>320</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/s41746-025-01731-x</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40442266</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12122910</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R18"><label>18.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Alami</surname><given-names>H</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Lehoux</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Miller</surname><given-names>FA</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shaw</surname><given-names>SE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Fortin</surname><given-names>JP</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>An urgent call for the environmental sustainability of health systems: a 'sextuple aim' to care for patients, costs, providers, population equity and the planet</article-title><source>Int J Health Plann Manage</source><month>Mar</month><year>2023</year><volume>38</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>289</fpage><lpage>295</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/hpm.3616</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36734815</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R19"><label>19.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Quentin</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Partanen</surname><given-names>VM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brownwood</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Klazinga</surname><given-names>N</given-names></name>
</person-group><part-title>Measuring healthcare quality</part-title><source>Improving Healthcare Quality in Europe: Characteristics, Effectiveness and Implementation of Different Strategies</source><publisher-name>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies</publisher-name><year>2019</year><fpage>31</fpage><lpage>62</lpage><comment>ISBN</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="isbn">9789289051750</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R20"><label>20.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Petrie</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Makanjuola</surname><given-names>O</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Laur</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Developing balanced quality indicators for monitoring virtual care in ambulatory care environments: modified Delphi panel process</article-title><source>J Med Internet Res</source><month>Jun</month><day>16</day><year>2025</year><volume>27</volume><elocation-id>e38657</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/38657</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40522721</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12209721</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R21"><label>21.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><article-title>Use of digital health tools in Europe: before, during and after COVID-19</article-title><publisher-name>European Observatory on Health Systems and Policies</publisher-name><year>2021</year><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/399df5c6-fd0e-4535-91f8-e7a44ab4ab1d/content" ext-link-type="uri">https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/399df5c6-fd0e-4535-91f8-e7a44ab4ab1d/content</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>18-06-2026</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref><ref id="R22"><label>22.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Claggett</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Petter</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Joshi</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ponzio</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kirkendall</surname><given-names>E</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>An infrastructure framework for remote patient monitoring interventions and research</article-title><source>J Med Internet Res</source><month>05</month><day>30</day><year>2024</year><volume>26</volume><elocation-id>e51234</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/51234</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38815263</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11176884</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R23"><label>23.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Mechanic</surname><given-names>OJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Persaud</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kimball</surname><given-names>AB</given-names></name>
</person-group><part-title>Telehealth sytems</part-title><source>StatPearls</source><publisher-name>StatPearls Publishing</publisher-name><year>2025</year><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK459384" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/books/NBK459384</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>18-06-2026</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref><ref id="R24"><label>24.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Liu</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ma</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Sun</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Zhang</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gao</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Xu</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Mapping the landscape of digital health intervention strategies: 25-year synthesis</article-title><source>J Med Internet Res</source><month>01</month><day>13</day><year>2025</year><volume>27</volume><elocation-id>e59027</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.2196/59027</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39804697</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11773286</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R25"><label>25.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Prinsen</surname><given-names>CAC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Vohra</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rose</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Core Outcome Measures in Effectiveness Trials (COMET) initiative: protocol for an international Delphi study to achieve consensus on how to select outcome measurement instruments for outcomes included in a “core outcome set”</article-title><source>Trials</source><month>Jun</month><day>25</day><year>2014</year><volume>15</volume><elocation-id>247</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/1745-6215-15-247</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24962012</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC4082295</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R26"><label>26.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gattrell</surname><given-names>WT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Logullo</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>van Zuuren</surname><given-names>EJ</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>ACCORD (Accurate Consensus Reporting Document): a reporting guideline for consensus methods in biomedicine developed via a modified Delphi</article-title><source>PLoS Med</source><month>01</month><year>2024</year><volume>21</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>e1004326</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pmed.1004326</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">38261576</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10805282</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R27"><label>27.</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>Referentenpanel [Article in Dutch]</article-title><source>Patiëntenfederatie Nederland</source><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.patientenfederatie.nl/praktische-hulp/referentenpanel" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.patientenfederatie.nl/praktische-hulp/referentenpanel</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>24-06-2026</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref><ref id="R28"><label>28.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Schifano</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Niederberger</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>How Delphi studies in the health sciences find consensus: a scoping review</article-title><source>Syst Rev</source><month>01</month><day>14</day><year>2025</year><volume>14</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>14</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13643-024-02738-3</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39810238</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11734368</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R29"><label>29.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>de Villiers</surname><given-names>MR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>de Villiers</surname><given-names>PJT</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kent</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The Delphi technique in health sciences education research</article-title><source>Med Teach</source><month>Nov</month><year>2005</year><volume>27</volume><issue>7</issue><fpage>639</fpage><lpage>643</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1080/13611260500069947</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">16332558</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R30"><label>30.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bakker</surname><given-names>MM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Luttikhuis</surname><given-names>T</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Putrik</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Consideration of health literacy in patient information: a mixed-methods study of COVID-19 crisis communication in Dutch rheumatology</article-title><source>BMC Rheumatol</source><month>Sep</month><day>7</day><year>2022</year><volume>6</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>52</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s41927-022-00283-x</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">36068591</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC9449268</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R31"><label>31.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Veugelers</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gaakeer</surname><given-names>MI</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Patka</surname><given-names>P</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Huijsman</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Improving design choices in Delphi studies in medicine: the case of an exemplary physician multi-round panel study with 100% response</article-title><source>BMC Med Res Methodol</source><month>Jun</month><day>15</day><year>2020</year><volume>20</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>156</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12874-020-01029-4</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">32539717</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC7294633</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R32"><label>32.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Pill</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The Delphi method: substance, context, a critique and an annotated bibliography</article-title><source>Socio-econ Plan Sci</source><month>Feb</month><year>1971</year><volume>5</volume><issue>1</issue><fpage>57</fpage><lpage>71</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0038-0121(71)90041-3</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R33"><label>33.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Rowe</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Wright</surname><given-names>G</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bolger</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Delphi: a reevaluation of research and theory</article-title><source>Technol Forecast Soc Change</source><month>05</month><year>1991</year><volume>39</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>235</fpage><lpage>251</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/0040-1625(91)90039-I</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R34"><label>34.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Diamond</surname><given-names>IR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Grant</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Feldman</surname><given-names>BM</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Defining consensus: a systematic review recommends methodologic criteria for reporting of Delphi studies</article-title><source>J Clin Epidemiol</source><month>Apr</month><year>2014</year><volume>67</volume><issue>4</issue><fpage>401</fpage><lpage>409</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jclinepi.2013.12.002</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24581294</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R35"><label>35.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Prorok</surname><given-names>JC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Williamson</surname><given-names>PR</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shea</surname><given-names>B</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>An international Delphi consensus process to determine a common data element and core outcome set for frailty: FOCUS (the Frailty Outcomes Consensus Project)</article-title><source>BMC Geriatr</source><month>Apr</month><day>5</day><year>2022</year><volume>22</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>284</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12877-022-02993-w</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">35382752</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC8985339</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R36"><label>36.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Shan</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Li</surname><given-names>Y</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ding</surname><given-names>D</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Patient satisfaction with hospital inpatient care: effects of trust, medical insurance and perceived quality of care</article-title><source>PLoS One</source><year>2016</year><volume>11</volume><issue>10</issue><elocation-id>e0164366</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1371/journal.pone.0164366</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">27755558</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC5068749</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R37"><label>37.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Terkola</surname><given-names>R</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Antoñanzas</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Postma</surname><given-names>M</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Stakeholder opinions on value in healthcare</article-title><source>Eur J Hosp Pharm</source><month>Mar</month><year>2019</year><volume>26</volume><issue>2</issue><fpage>79</fpage><lpage>84</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/ejhpharm-2017-001295</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31157104</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6452345</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R38"><label>38.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Cohen</surname><given-names>ES</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kringos</surname><given-names>DS</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Grandiek</surname><given-names>F</given-names></name>
<etal>et al</etal>
</person-group><article-title>Patients’ attitudes towards integrating environmental sustainability into healthcare decision-making: an interview study</article-title><source>Health Expect</source><month>Feb</month><year>2025</year><volume>28</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>e70155</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1111/hex.70155</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">39828934</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC11743189</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R39"><label>39.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>van Nieuwenhuizen</surname><given-names>KE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Friedericy</surname><given-names>HJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>van der Eijk</surname><given-names>AC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jansen</surname><given-names>FW</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>van den Akker-van Marle</surname><given-names>ME</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Decision-making factors in surgical techniques and attitudes towards environmental sustainability</article-title><source>Ann Surg</source><month>Mar</month><day>11</day><year>2025</year><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1097/SLA.0000000000006691</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40067776</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC13344403</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R40"><label>40.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>van Bree</surname><given-names>EM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Snijder</surname><given-names>LE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ter Haak</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Atsma</surname><given-names>DE</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Brakema</surname><given-names>EA</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>The environmental impact of telemonitoring vs. on-site cardiac follow-up: a mixed-method study</article-title><source>Eur Heart J Digit Health</source><year>2025</year><volume>6</volume><issue>3</issue><fpage>496</fpage><lpage>507</lpage><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1093/ehjdh/ztaf012</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40395419</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12088715</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R41"><label>41.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Beune</surname><given-names>IM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Jansen</surname><given-names>L</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Grooten</surname><given-names>I</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Ganzevoort</surname><given-names>W</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Painter</surname><given-names>RC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gordijn</surname><given-names>S</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Testing the applicability and additional value of a consultation round after the consensus meeting in the development of two core outcome sets</article-title><source>BMJ Open</source><month>05</month><day>24</day><year>2023</year><volume>13</volume><issue>5</issue><elocation-id>e060531</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2021-060531</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37225270</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10230873</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R42"><label>42.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Gobeil-Lavoie</surname><given-names>AP</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Chouinard</surname><given-names>MC</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Danish</surname><given-names>A</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Hudon</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Characteristics of self-management among patients with complex health needs: a thematic analysis review</article-title><source>BMJ Open</source><month>05</month><day>24</day><year>2019</year><volume>9</volume><issue>5</issue><elocation-id>e028344</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1136/bmjopen-2018-028344</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">31129599</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC6538095</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R43"><label>43.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Theunissen</surname><given-names>MCM</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Koks-Leensen</surname><given-names>MCJ</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>van Geenen</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Leusink</surname><given-names>GL</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Naaldenberg</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Bevelander</surname><given-names>KE</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Engaging underrepresented populations in public health monitoring: strategies for people with mild intellectual disability or low literacy skills</article-title><source>Int J Equity Health</source><month>07</month><day>14</day><year>2025</year><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>204</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s12939-025-02578-0</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">40660218</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC12257827</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R44"><label>44.</label><element-citation publication-type="journal"><person-group person-group-type="author">
<name name-style="western"><surname>Del Grande</surname><given-names>C</given-names></name>
<name name-style="western"><surname>Kaczorowski</surname><given-names>J</given-names></name>
</person-group><article-title>Rating versus ranking in a Delphi survey: a randomized controlled trial</article-title><source>Trials</source><month>Aug</month><day>18</day><year>2023</year><volume>24</volume><issue>1</issue><elocation-id>543</elocation-id><comment>doi</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1186/s13063-023-07442-6</pub-id><comment>Medline</comment><pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">37596699</pub-id><pub-id pub-id-type="pmcid">PMC10436639</pub-id></element-citation></ref><ref id="R45"><label>45.</label><element-citation publication-type="webpage"><article-title>Consortium Waardebepaling [Article in Dutch]</article-title><source>Vilans</source><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.vilans.nl/wat-doen-we/projecten/consortium-waardebepaling" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.vilans.nl/wat-doen-we/projecten/consortium-waardebepaling</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>11-10-2025</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref><ref id="R46"><label>46.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><article-title>Telehealth quality of care tool</article-title><publisher-name>World Health Organization</publisher-name><year>2024</year><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/7e6d0958-8941-469c-ac0f-e0c879b3dad4/content" ext-link-type="uri">https://iris.who.int/server/api/core/bitstreams/7e6d0958-8941-469c-ac0f-e0c879b3dad4/content</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>18-06-2026</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref><ref id="R47"><label>47.</label><element-citation publication-type="book"><article-title>e-health waardenmodel [Report in Dutch]</article-title><publisher-name>Erasmus School of Health Policy &amp; Management</publisher-name><year>2020</year><comment>URL</comment><ext-link xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="https://www.eur.nl/eshpm/media/89013" ext-link-type="uri">https://www.eur.nl/eshpm/media/89013</ext-link><comment>Accessed</comment><date-in-citation>18-06-2026</date-in-citation></element-citation></ref></ref-list></back></article>